Guide to the John W. Burton papers, 1937-1988
George Mason University Libraries
- JOHN W. BURTON COLLECTION
  - " 1970's CORRESPONDENCE AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS" (Folder 7, Box 13)
  - " EIRE- INVOLVEMENT REACTION " (Folder 1, Box 14)
  - "THIRD PARTY CONSULTATION" (Folder 2, Box 14)
  - " INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATION: A CONCEPTUAL APPROACH" (Folder 3, Box 14)
  - "POVERTY,DEPRIVATION AND THE CRISIS IN SOCIAL WORK:POLICY OR STRUCTURE ?" 1974 (Folder 4, Box 14)
  - " GIBRALTAR -BY WAY OF EXAMPLE" 1971 (Folder 5, Box 14)
  - " ORDER WITHOUT LAW" 1973 (Folder 6, Box 14)
  - " FUNCTIONALISM AND THE RESOLUTION ON CONFLICT" 1970 (Folder 7, Box 14)
  - " RESOLVING CONFLICT IN BRITAIN " 1970 (Folder 8, Box 14)
  - " THE EROSION OF AUTHORITY" 1973 (Folder 9, Box 14)
  - " CONTENDING APPROACHES TO SOCIAL WORK: A FRAMEWORK FOR ANALYSIS" 1973 (Folder 10, Box 14)
  - " ORDER WITHOUT LAW" 1973 (Folder 11, Box 14)
  - " PEACEMAKING: SOME PROBLEMS OF THIRD PARTY ACTIVITY " 1975 (Folder 12, Box 14)
  - " WHY WE FAILED " 1979 (Folder 13, Box 14)
  - " MOSCOW" (Folder 14, Box 14)
  - " MOSCOW" (Folder 15, Box 14)
  - "1980's CORRESPONDENCE AND MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS" (Folder 16, Box 14)
  - "MARTIN ROBERTSON" (Folder 17, Box 14)
  - " 1980'S CHARITIES ACT COMMISSION " (Folder 18, Box 14)
  - "TOWARDS OBJECTIVE CRITERIA IN SOCIAL SCIENCES OR THE INDIVIDUAL AS THE INDEPENDENT VARIABLE" 1980 (Folder 19, Box 14)
  - " THE AFGHANISTAN TURMOIL " 1980 (Folder 1, Box 15)
  - "THE NEUTRALITY - INDEPENDENCE DEBATE" (Folder 2, Box 15)
  - " WAR AVOIDANCE - THE SECOND TRACK,INTRODUCTION" 1981 (Folder 3, Box 15)
  - " TOWARDS AN OBJECTIVE SOCIAL SCIENCE " 1981 (Folder 4, Box 15)
  - " THE PHILOSOPHY OF DISPUTES RESOLUTION " 1982 (Folder 5, Box 15)
  - " PROMOTING THE SELF-REALIZATION OF HUMAN NEEDS AND VALUES IN THE GLOBAL ORDER " 1983 (Folder 6, Box 15)
  - " PROTRACTED CONFLICTS: COMPLEXITIES OR PROCESS? " 1985 (Folder 7, Box 15)
  - " PROCEDURES FOR FACILITATED INTERNATIONAL CONFLICT RESOLUTION " 1980 (Folder 8, Box 15)
  - " RULES OF PROCEDURES FOR FACILITATED INTERNATIONAL CONFLICT RESOLUTIONS " 1984 (Folder 9, Box 15)
  - " PROCEDURES FOR FACILITATED INTERNATIONAL CONFLICT RESOLUTION " 1985 (Folder 10, Box 15)
  - " PROCEDURES FOR FACILITATED INTERNATIONAL CONFLICT RESOLUTION " 1985 (Folder 11, Box 15)
  - " WHAT TO DO ABOUT DISPUTES THAT ARE NON-NEGOTIABLE " 1986 (Folder 12, Box 15)
  - " GENERIC THEORY: THE BASIS OF CONFLICT RESOLUTION " 1986 (Folder 13, Box 15)
  - " REPRESSION OF HUMAN NEEDS: SYSTEM SURVIVAL OR DESTRUCTION " 1980 (Folder 14, Box 15)
  - " AN INTROSPECTIVE HISTORY OF THOUGHT ,TEACHING AND LANGUAGE OF CONFLICT RESOLUTION ,SPECIAL PROBLEM OF LEADERSHIP AND THE MISSION OF THE CENTER AND PhD OPPORTUNITIES " 1991 (Folder 15, Box 15)
  - " UNWINNABLE WARS: IRAQ AS A CASE STUDY " 1980 (Folder 16, Box 15)
  - " WORLD SOCIETY AND HUMAN NEEDS " 1991 (Folder 17, Box 15)
  - " THE ETHNICITY PROBLEM: MAJORITY GOVERNMENT VERSUS DEMOCRACY " 1991 (Folder 18, Box 15)
  - " CONFLICT RESOLUTION AS A POLITICAL PHILOSOPHY " 1990 (Folder 19, Box 15)
  - " RESTRUCTURING AS A POLITICAL PROCESS ETHNICITY AS A CASE STUDY " 1992 (Folder 20, Box 15)
  - " THE CONFLICT PREVENTION AS A POLITICAL SYSTEM " 1992 (Folder 21, Box 15)
  - " THE CIVILIZATIONS IN CRISIS :TOWARDS PROBLEM SOLVING " 1995 (Folder 22, Box 15)
  - " BEHIND UNITED STATES FOREIGN POLICIES: THE VIEW OF A FOREIGNER " 1980 (Folder 23, Box 15)
  - " THE MORALITY OF MEDIATION BY KEITH WEBB " 1984 (Folder 1, Box 16)
  - "MEDIATION: A VIABLE PROCESS FOR THE RESOLUTION OF COMMUNITY CONFLICT BY WILLIAM F.LINCOLN" 1984 (Folder 2, Box 16)
  - "IMPARTIAL INTERVENTION INTO COMMUNITY CONFLICT BY PETER RIP AND WILLIAM F. LINCOLN " (Folder 3, Box 16)
  - " FUTURE DIRECTIONS IN CONFLICT AND PEACE STUDIES BY KENNETH E. BODING" (Folder 4, Box 16)
  - "THE CONDITIONS,CRITERIA AND DIALECTICS OF HUMAN DIGNITY BY Herbert C. ELAN" (Folder 5, Box 16)
  - " THE PHYSIOLOGY OF VIOLENCE BY K.E. COYER " (Folder 6, Box 16)
  - " SCIENCE,WORLD POLITICS AND HUMAN RIGHTS BY RICHARD J. SELTZER " (Folder 7, Box 16)
  - " THE ENTRY PROBLEM:A FRAMEWORK FOR ANA LYSING ADVERSARIES DECISION ON MEDIATIVE INITIATIVES BY Cohn B. STEPHENS " (Folder 8, Box 16)
  - " HYPERGAMES AS AN AID TO MEDIATION ? BY PETER G. BENNETT " (Folder 9, Box 16)
  - " SETTLERS AND THE FAILURE OF BRITISH AND FRENCH STATE BUILDING IN IRELAND AND ALGERIA BY IAN LUSTICK " (Folder 10, Box 16)
  - "A PSYCHIATRIC MODEL FOR INTERCESSION IN INTERGROUP CONFLICT BY BRYANT WEDGE,MD " (Folder 11, Box 16)
  - " WORLD SOCIETY, CONFLICT AND Cohn BURTON AIDES " (Folder 12, Box 16)
  - " SYSTEMS,STATES,DIPLOMACY AND ROLES: REVIEWS " (Folder 13, Box 16)
  - " REVIEWS " [PART 1 OF 3] (Folder 14, Box 16)
  - " REVIEWS " [PART 2 OF 3] (Folder 15, Box 16)
  - " REVIEWS " [PART 3 OF 3] (Folder 16, Box 16)
  - " RESTRICTIVE INTERVENTION BY Cohn BURTON " (Folder 1, Box 17)
  - " THE EUROPEAN COMMUNITY" [BROCHURE] (Folder 2, Box 17)